<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Mac Strelioff</title>
    <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Mac Strelioff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 08:28:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Computer Science</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 08:28:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/computer-science/</guid>
      <description>Foundations Complexity Computational Complexity Constant Time: O(1) Logrithmic Time: O(log(n)) Polynomial Time: O(n), O(n^2), … Exponential Time: \(O(x^n)\)   Data Structures Lists and Dictionaries Queues and Stacks Graphs and Trees  Sorting  Searching Linear Search: Binary Search Graph Search Breadth First (BFS) and queues Depth First (DFS) DFS vs BFS Examples:  Pointers  Algorithms TODO / Other Topics: Recursion; Dijkstra’s algorithm dynamic programming (knapsack problem, Fibonacci sequence) Functional programming  Tools Git and GitHub SQL General Structure of SQL querys Aggregation functions Window functions Tricks:   Resources   Foundations Data type manipulation (char, string, numeric, binary, ascii) regular expressions;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instacart Notes</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/instacart-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 12:57:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/instacart-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>TODO:  Check out info from blog Read articles on their DS blog LinkedIn application for data scientist Instacart posting for data scientist LinkedIn app for analyst   Recruiter call “Just be prepared to share with me what you are looking for, what is exciting to you and feel free to have questions ready about the team, role, business etc”
 Groceries have been hard for internet companies to get right – it’s exciting to see Instacart managing this well, and I’d be excited to be a part of this technological revolution of grocery delivery   More about role?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Statistics</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/probability-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 11:02:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/probability-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Probability Foundations Probability Rules Probability Functions Expectation Variance Information Theory  Causal Inference Assumptions and key terms Common Methods Diff in Diff Causal Impact Synthetic Controls IV Analysis Regression Discontinuity Fixed Effects Regression First differences Random Effects Propensity Score Matching Microsoft DoWhy   Experiment Design Foundations Concerns Treatment Units Generative Model and Adjustment Variables Common Designs Assignment Mechanism Duration Integrety Checks Maximum Likelihood versus Bayes’ Estimators  GLMs Common Tests t-test ANOVA Linear Model Z test for proportions Chi-Square Logistic Regression Likelihood Ratio and Bayes Factors always valid p-values (ck optimizely white paper)  Different Estimands For CI more on variance Emperical Variance Estimation Mixed Effects Models Effiencicy or Variance Reduction GLMs  Causal Inference Methods Difference in Differences Causal Impact Synthetic Controls Propensity Score Matching Fixed Effects Regression Instrumental variables Regression Discontinuity    Probability Foundations A random variable random variable is a variable with an unknown value, but known possible values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wealthfront Notes</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/wealthfront-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 20:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/wealthfront-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>TODO:  Looking for: “You enjoy mentoring others on subjects such as causal inference, experimental design, data visualization or behavioral psychology”  Make a few videos on experimentation and causal inference  Work on: “You subscribe to Wealthfront’s values and mission and can articulate the reasons why, and have an understanding of our product, business model and key metrics”   Job Description Projects, Tasks, and Data  Work closely with a cross-functional growth team of marketers, product managers, and engineers to generate new ideas for growth especially top of funnel, translating open-ended business issues into data questions, identifying practical analytic and A/B testing approaches to validate the ideas, and defining ongoing checks post-implementation to ensure that the growth mechanisms are working as planned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 14:21:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Considerations Bias-variance trade-off Overfitting and Underfitting Cost Functions and Metrics Feature Engineering Seperability Assumptions about form of relationship   Unsupervised Clustering k-means Agglomerative Devisive  Matrix Decomposition PCA Principle Components Analysis SVD Singular Value Decomposition  Text-based LDA Latent Direchilote Analysis LSA Latent Semantic Analysis   Supervised Regression Linear Support Vector Machine (SVM)  Classification Naive Bayes Discriminant Analysis KNN Logistic Regression   Ensemble Methods Trees and Forests Regression Classification   Open ended Template Raw data structure?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Interviewing</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/behavioral-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 13:59:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/behavioral-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Principles Evaluation  Common Behavioral Questions “Tell me a little about your background.” Child bandits:  “Tell me about the project you worked on at Insight.” “Why are you interested in a career as a data scientist?” “Tell me about your research / talk to me about your last role.” “Why are you interested in joining this company?” “Talk about a time you were on a team that struggled with effective communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product Sense</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/business-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 12:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/business-sense/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Example The YouTube recommendation algorithm favors videos with high watchtime.
video on the algorithm.
 titles thumbnails descriptions how other viewers seem to enjoy it likes/dislikes comments view duration  series on how search and discovery works.
Search:
 videos ranked match between query and title, description tip: can make videos on trending content. tip: can use google to find common search terms. engagement and watch time  Suggested videos:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkedIn Notes</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/linkedin-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2019 18:56:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/linkedin-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>Company Visit Chris info –  Recruiter Call Recruiter emails II &amp;amp; III – Interviews Schedule and interviewers: 10:00-10:45 | Host Leader | Joonhyung Lim 10:45-11:30 | Statistical Modeling | Dongping (sunny) Jing and Caitlin Crump: 11:30-12:30 | Lunch | Nuo Wang 12:30-1:15 | Data Manipulation | Xianyun Mao: 1:15-2:00 | Statistics &amp;amp; A/B Testing | | Qiannan Yin and Yuan Chai: 2:00-2:45 | Analytics Case Study | Gigi Zhang: Users Current issues Ideas and excitement Excitement from Recruiter  Onsite Glassdoor interview questions   Knowledge gaps Next steps   Company Visit Chris info –  DS people generally get interviewed on computer engineering topics – eg implementing data structures from scratch, … Interview centrally for AI organization, then get matched with a team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yelp Notes</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/yelp-deep-dive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 10:16:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/yelp-deep-dive/</guid>
      <description>TODO:  compute common business metrics from Yelp dataset. Product deep dive   Company Visit Business Model, Culture, and Vision  Mission: Connect people with great local places Main source of revenue is business ads, overview of offerings here More services for businesses Want: openness, curiosity, approachable DS team has “Office hours” to facilitate communication Journal clubs and learning groups Can move to PM or ML teams   Projects, Tasks, and Data  Working on personalization e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>