<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>InsightStudyings on Mac Strelioff</title>
    <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/</link>
    <description>Recent content in InsightStudyings on Mac Strelioff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 09:00:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 09:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/computer-science/</guid>
      <description>Foundations Searching Sorting Sort Algorithms Search Algorithms Ranking Algorithms Recommendation  Data Structures Algorithms Tools   Foundations Data type manipulation (char, string, numeric) regular expressions;
basic structures (tuples, list, arrays, dict), list comprehensions,
Complexity + O(N) notation
 Searching binary search,
 print(1+5)  &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; 6  Sorting sorting (bubble, selection, insertion, merge, quick)
Sorting and graph algos (depth-first and breadth-first seach)
sorting (heap, tim)
Sort Algorithms Lots of sort algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Statistics</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/probability-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 08:39:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/probability-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Fermi problems (order of magnitude)
Probability Foundations combinatorics (permutations and combinations)
Probability Rules basic probability rules
 Odds and other transformations odds, log odds, relative risk, … .
 Expectation and Variance expectation, variance, conditional or iterated expectations, law of total variance, variance of multiple variables
  Experimental Design Estimands  Control Groups Propensity matching
 Effiencicy e.g. with a two sample t-test, \(Y_t - Y_{t-1} = \beta_0\), versus a model \(Y_t = \beta_0 + \beta_1 Y_{t-1}\)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 08:32:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Considerations Bias-variance trade-off Overfitting and Underfitting Cost Functions and Metrics Feature Engineering Seperability Assumptions about form of relationship   Unsupervised Clustering k-means Agglomerative Devisive  Matrix Decomposition PCA Principle Components Analysis SVD Singular Value Decomposition  Text-based LDA Latent Direchilote Analysis LSA Latent Semantic Analysis   Supervised Regression Linear Support Vector Machine (SVM)  Classification Naive Bayes KNN Logistic Regression   Ensemble Methods Trees and Forests Regression Classification     Considerations Bias-variance trade-off  Overfitting and Underfitting Cross Validation; Classification</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Interviewing</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/behavioral-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 08:01:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/behavioral-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Tell me about yourself, your academic research, why data science?; 30 second elevator pitch vs. 2 minute phone screen/on-site
Why this company? what value can you add? Tell me about a time when…
STAR chart (Situation, Task, Action, Result)
Mock interviews: Practice, practice, practice</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Sense</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/business-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 19:40:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/business-sense/</guid>
      <description>Churn, engagement, search engine optimization (SEO), customer lifetime value (LTV), key-performance indicators (KPIs), funnel analysis
Experiment design, A/A and A/B testing, power analysis;
ML focused business case study (features, algorithms, validation, value), business focused data challenges
Giulio Palombo’s collection of business focused data challenges
Company deep dives; data+schema brainstorming; ML algorithms; Insights;
Company blogs are a great resource: check out how StitchFix, Instacart use data science.
More company deep dives!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>