<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Mac Strelioff</title>
    <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Mac Strelioff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:59:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Business Sense</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/business-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 08:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/business-sense/</guid>
      <description>Churn, engagement, search engine optimization (SEO), customer lifetime value (LTV), key-performance indicators (KPIs), funnel analysis
Experiment design, A/A and A/B testing, power analysis;
ML focused business case study (features, algorithms, validation, value), business focused data challenges
Template Value of a new feature e.g. higher engagement, better labels for training data or other user behaivors
 Deamand for a feature  Surveys Focus Groups UX interviews / shadows Retrospective analysis (looking at past user behavior)   Treatment Design How exactly will this be implemented in the treatment group?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computer Science</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/computer-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2019 19:19:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/computer-science/</guid>
      <description>Foundations Complexity Computational Complexity Constant Time: O(1) Logrithmic Time: O(log(n)) Polynomial Time: O(n), O(n^2), … Exponential Time: \(O(x^n)\) Logrithmic Time: O(log(N))   Data Structures Trees Binary search trees  Database and SQL General Structure of SQL querys Aggregation functions   Sorting Searching Ranking Algorithms Recommendation Algorithms Tools General Practice Problems   Foundations Data type manipulation (char, string, numeric, binary, ascii) regular expressions;
Complexity The worst-case complexity of an algorithm is represented with big-O notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>Considerations Bias-variance trade-off Overfitting and Underfitting Cost Functions and Metrics Feature Engineering Seperability Assumptions about form of relationship   Unsupervised Clustering k-means Agglomerative Devisive  Matrix Decomposition PCA Principle Components Analysis SVD Singular Value Decomposition  Text-based LDA Latent Direchilote Analysis LSA Latent Semantic Analysis   Supervised Regression Linear Support Vector Machine (SVM)  Classification Naive Bayes Discriminant Analysis KNN Logistic Regression   Ensemble Methods Trees and Forests Regression Classification   Open ended Template Raw data structure?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Interviewing</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/behavioral-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 09:02:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/behavioral-interviews/</guid>
      <description>Tell me about yourself, your academic research, why data science?; 30 second elevator pitch vs. 2 minute phone screen/on-site
Why this company? what value can you add? Tell me about a time when…
STAR chart (Situation, Task, Action, Result)
Mock interviews: Practice, practice, practice
Common Behavioral Questions “Tell me a little about your background.” PhD projects can include:
Child bandits: Bandit tasks are a common paradigm for studying individual level decision making and making claims about the way people make decisions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Statistics</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/probability-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 12:58:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/insightstudying/probability-statistics/</guid>
      <description>Probability Foundations Probability Rules Odds and other transformations Expectation and Variance Central limit theorem  Experiment Design Objective, demand, and value Constructs, metrics, and scoping User flow and target metrics Invariants Confounding variables Precision variables  Metric Validation Conditions Treatment Units Assignment Mechanism Population Cohorts Synthetic Control Groups Limitations   Implementation Size Duration Temporal variation Optional stopping  Estimands Effiencicy  Testing Binary or Proportions Fisher’s Z  Real-Valued Regression   Linear Models GLMs Emperical Variance Estimation   Fermi problems (order of magnitude)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>