<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Mac Strelioff</title>
    <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Mac Strelioff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:52:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/MacStrelioff/unlisted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DRAFT OF: Cookie Clicker Bot</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/cookie-clicker-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:52:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/cookie-clicker-bot/</guid>
      <description>ADD PROJECT TO GIT HUB, AND LINK TO IT Overview Background and Setup Cookie Clicker Game  Strategies Naive Max revenue per second Min wait time until the highest rps option  Performance   ADD PROJECT TO GIT HUB, AND LINK TO IT  Overview Lately I’ve been interested in writing algorithms that interact with websites. The game Cookie Clicker is a great testing ground for such algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandit Algos for Estimation, Hypothesis Testing, and Decision Making</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/banditalgos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/banditalgos/</guid>
      <description>Sources / Alternatives  Netflix Experimentation and Sequential Testing Optamizely Google Analytics   TODO: redo in Python, make an agent that uses each strategy as a method. Build the agent throughout the script.   Intro Scientists and business students are trained in decision making from an outdated perspective – classical decision making based on p-values.
(make a case against p-values – inflated error rates, incoherence, difficulty integrating with expected value)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Testing as Classifier Evaluation</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/hypothesesaremodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/hypothesesaremodels/</guid>
      <description>Overview Here I breed ideas from hypothesis testing, with those from the machine learning community on evaluating classifiers.
 Hypothesis Testing Hypothesis testing is based on a notion of accepting or rejecting a hypothesis based on data from an experiment.
accept, reject
Type I error –
Type II error –
\(\alpha\) \(\beta\) power
base rates
false discovery rate
 Classification Evaluation Calssification evaluation is based on selecting a model based on performance in out-of-sample performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insight</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/insight/</guid>
      <description>Overview: Made this doc to document my journey through the Insight Data Science program.
1-3 work on project and professional skills. Week 4 work on demo. Weeks 5-8 deliver demo, work on interview preparation.
 Professional Skills Mindset (Day 1: 6/3/2019) Imposter syndrome
Fail quickly and iterate
Open mindedness – new problem space, …
Adaptability, identify weakenesses and adapt
 Applying Identify strengths, and demonstrantions of value to a company</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Metrics Through YouTube Creator</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/metricsthroughyoutubecreator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/metricsthroughyoutubecreator/</guid>
      <description> What are Metrics? Metrics are how the data scientist communicates with project managers.
Two categories; success and tracking.
Goals are defined in terms of metrics, and user experience is understood through metrics.
Success Metrics  Tracking Metrics   Metrics for Goals  Metrics for Insights  Communicating Metrics Idea from:
 Add metrics from google analytics, and youtube creator.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Autoclicker</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/autoclicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/autoclicker/</guid>
      <description> Overview Madean autoclicker to play cookie clicker…
Cookie clicker game.. talk through code..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Information</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/its-a-null-world-after-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/its-a-null-world-after-all/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a series of questions about hypothesis testing, parils of p-hacking, and an argument against a publication requirement for graduation..
What is a p-value?
What is power?
Assume all hypotheses in a field are false. Using z-tests or t-tests, testing at the \(\alpha=.05\) level, …
How many experiments, on average, would a graduate student have to run in order to find three significant effects?
What kind of distribution is this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Information</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/probabilityandinformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/probabilityandinformation/</guid>
      <description>Probability Theory and Information Theory Types of Probabilities and Their Computations motivation? Many important variables (future income, GDP, who I’ll marry, whether I’ll get sick, what disease I have given some symptoms, …)
 Randomness, Event Spaces, and Probability motivating example.. Imagine that a vaccine against a dangerous disease recently becomes available. However, there is a small risk that the vaccine will produce a condition just as bad as the disease itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommending: Searching, Sorting, Ranking</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/searchsortrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/searchsortrank/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation Lots of recommendation algorithms
Data science methods play a major role in discovering recommendations for users.
Econ, compliments and substitutes (competitors).
Types of recommendation; compliments (these go together), competitors (you might also like…), temporal (might buy this again in the future). Horizontal and vertical focus
Temporal involves forecasting, which is a topic for another post.
 Sort Algorithms Lots of sort algorithms
 Search Algorithms Lots of search algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like Bayesian Statistics</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/why_bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/why_bayes/</guid>
      <description> Overview Madean autoclicker to play cookie clicker…
Coherent Examples where frequentist stats is incoherent?
 Flexible  easy to model complex processes easy to test non-standard hypotheses, e.g. “does every”, or “two groups higher, one group lower”   Integration with decision theory Thompson sampling example
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>