<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Overview on Mac Strelioff</title>
    <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Overview on Mac Strelioff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 13:27:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/MacStrelioff/unlisted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Buying a Condo</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/home_buying/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 13:27:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/home_buying/</guid>
      <description>  Important Features Pre-approval Places I like   Important Features  Proximity to Pinterest, 505 Brannan St, San Francisco, CA 94107 In unit washer and dryer Wood floors   Pre-approval  Places I like  888 7th street
 Possibly 766 Harrison Street, Apt 405
   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YouTube Strategy</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/youtube_strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/youtube_strategy/</guid>
      <description>Planned Videos “About Me” Channel Video Data Science Interview Walkthrough Series “Data Scientist Interview Walkthrough: Intro” Data Scientist Interview Walkthrough: Probability Question Set 4 Why do you want this role?  Current Topics in Data Science Explain some research at Pintrest  Data Science Topics and Concepts What is Probability and What is a Probability Function? What is a Power Analysis? (Explained at 3 levels of difficulty) What is a sampling distribution?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandit Algos for Estimation, Hypothesis Testing, and Decision Making</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/banditalgos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/banditalgos/</guid>
      <description>Sources / Alternatives  Netflix Experimentation and Sequential Testing Optamizely Google Analytics   TODO: redo in Python, make an agent that uses each strategy as a method. Build the agent throughout the script.   Intro Scientists and business students are trained in decision making from an outdated perspective – classical decision making based on p-values.
(make a case against p-values – inflated error rates, incoherence, difficulty integrating with expected value)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandit Algos for Estimation, Hypothesis Testing, and Decision Making</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/runningremotejobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/runningremotejobs/</guid>
      <description> Sources / Alternatives https://superuser.com/questions/214759/connect-to-another-mac-via-terminal
Useful terminal commands:
sudo shutdown # powers off  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypothesis Testing as Classifier Evaluation</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/hypothesesaremodels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/hypothesesaremodels/</guid>
      <description>Overview Here I breed ideas from hypothesis testing, with those from the machine learning community on evaluating classifiers.
 Hypothesis Testing Hypothesis testing is based on a notion of accepting or rejecting a hypothesis based on data from an experiment.
accept, reject
Type I error –
Type II error –
\(\alpha\) \(\beta\) power
base rates
false discovery rate
 Classification Evaluation Calssification evaluation is based on selecting a model based on performance in out-of-sample performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insight</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/insight/</guid>
      <description>Overview: Made this doc to document my journey through the Insight Data Science program.
1-3 work on project and professional skills. Week 4 work on demo. Weeks 5-8 deliver demo, work on interview preparation.
 Professional Skills Mindset (Day 1: 6/3/2019) Imposter syndrome
Fail quickly and iterate
Open mindedness – new problem space, …
Adaptability, identify weakenesses and adapt
 Applying Identify strengths, and demonstrantions of value to a company</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommending: Searching, Sorting, Ranking</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/searchsortrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/searchsortrank/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation Lots of recommendation algorithms
Data science methods play a major role in discovering recommendations for users.
Econ, compliments and substitutes (competitors).
Types of recommendation; compliments (these go together), competitors (you might also like…), temporal (might buy this again in the future). Horizontal and vertical focus
Temporal involves forecasting, which is a topic for another post.
 Sort Algorithms Lots of sort algorithms
 Search Algorithms Lots of search algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like Bayesian Statistics</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/why_bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/why_bayes/</guid>
      <description> Overview Coherent Examples where frequentist stats is incoherent?
 Flexible  easy to model complex processes easy to test non-standard hypotheses, e.g. “does every”, or “two groups higher, one group lower”   Integration with decision theory Thompson sampling example
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>