<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unlisteds on Mac Strelioff</title>
    <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unlisteds on Mac Strelioff</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/MacStrelioff/unlisted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandit Algos for Estimation, Hypothesis Testing, and Decision Making</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/banditalgos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/banditalgos/</guid>
      <description>Sources / Alternatives  Netflix Experimentation and Sequential Testing Optamizely Google Analytics   TODO: redo in Python, make an agent that uses each strategy as a method. Build the agent throughout the script.   Intro Scientists and business students are trained in decision making from an outdated perspective – classical decision making based on p-values.
(make a case against p-values – inflated error rates, incoherence, difficulty integrating with expected value)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insight</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/insight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/insight/</guid>
      <description>Overview: Professional Skills Mindset (Day 1: 6/3/2019) Applying LinkedIn Resume Pitch Demos  Opportunities: Networking and Company Visits Profiling an opportunity   Project Ideation (5/21-6/5) Prediction Market Sentiment Analysis Stats Website Bandit Analysis Car price recommender Kaggle competition?  Selection Guiding principles for analysis Thinking about Variables Thinking about Models  Consulting Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Final Deliverable Presentation or Demo Business Value Statement   Interview Preparation   Overview: Made this doc to document my journey through the Insight Data Science program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Metrics Through YouTube Creator</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/metricsthroughyoutubecreator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/metricsthroughyoutubecreator/</guid>
      <description> What are Metrics? Metrics are how the data scientist communicates with project managers.
Two categories; success and tracking.
Goals are defined in terms of metrics, and user experience is understood through metrics.
Success Metrics  Tracking Metrics   Metrics for Goals  Metrics for Insights  Communicating Metrics Idea from:
 Add metrics from google analytics, and youtube creator.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Autoclicker</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/autoclicker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/autoclicker/</guid>
      <description>  Overview Cookie clicker game..    Overview Madean autoclicker to play cookie clicker…
Cookie clicker game.. talk through code..
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and Information</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/probabilityandinformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/probabilityandinformation/</guid>
      <description>Probability Theory and Information Theory Types of Probabilities and Their Computations motivation? Many important variables (future income, GDP, who I’ll marry, whether I’ll get sick, what disease I have given some symptoms, …)
 Randomness, Event Spaces, and Probability motivating example.. Imagine that a vaccine against a dangerous disease recently becomes available. However, there is a small risk that the vaccine will produce a condition just as bad as the disease itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommending: Searching, Sorting, Ranking</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/searchsortrank/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/searchsortrank/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation Sort Algorithms Search Algorithms Ranking Algorithms   Recommendation Lots of recommendation algorithms
Data science methods play a major role in discovering recommendations for users.
Econ, compliments and substitutes (competitors).
Types of recommendation; compliments (these go together), competitors (you might also like…), temporal (might buy this again in the future). Horizontal and vertical focus
Temporal involves forecasting, which is a topic for another post.
 Sort Algorithms Lots of sort algorithms</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Like Bayesian Statistics</title>
      <link>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/why_bayes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/MacStrelioff/unlisted/why_bayes/</guid>
      <description>  Overview Coherent Flexible Integration with decision theory    Overview Madean autoclicker to play cookie clicker…
Coherent Examples where frequentist stats is incoherent?
 Flexible  easy to model complex processes easy to test non-standard hypotheses, e.g. “does every”, or “two groups higher, one group lower”   Integration with decision theory Thompson sampling example
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>